<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zheng He Hu</title><link>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/</link><description>Recent content on Zheng He Hu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://zhenghe.hu/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thinking, Fast and Slow</title><link>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Thinking-Fast-and-Slow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Thinking-Fast-and-Slow/</guid><description>Author: [[Daniel Kahneman]] Human have two primary systems for thinking. System 1 System 2 Operates automatically Allocated attention No voluntary control Corrects intuitive predictions Lazy Hard worker Diffuse thinking Focused thinking What you see is all there is People tend to make decisions and judgments based on personal bias and intuition, instead of facts and statistics.</description></item><item><title>Daniel Kahneman</title><link>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Daniel-Kahneman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Daniel-Kahneman/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ego is the Enemy</title><link>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Ego-is-the-Enemy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Ego-is-the-Enemy/</guid><description>Author: [[Ryan Holiday]] Talk, talk, talk, talk Silence is a strength Just spending hours talking about doing something doesn&amp;rsquo;t count as doing it To be or to do? Pretend to have virtues or be virtuous? Try to impress people of be truly impressive? Not actually good examples &amp;ldquo;to be&amp;rdquo; has compromises &amp;ldquo;to do&amp;rdquo; means having a purpose, there is only one way, but is hard Become a student Never cease to improve Never think of knowing enough Have a lesser whom to teach, an equal to confront and a better to learn from &amp;ldquo;It is impossible to learn that which one thinks one already knows&amp;rdquo; - Epictetus Be open to feedback Don&amp;rsquo;t be passionate Be reasonable Don&amp;rsquo;t be passionate, have a purpose Passion highlights the ego e.</description></item><item><title>Ryan Holiday</title><link>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Ryan-Holiday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Ryan-Holiday/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Amazon Aurora</title><link>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Amazon-Aurora/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Amazon-Aurora/</guid><description>Why? Disaster recovery
Aurora PostgreSQL Disaster Recovery solutions using Amazon Aurora Global Database | Amazon Web Services
Takeaway from above: PostgreSQL logical replication and the storage-based replication that Aurora Global Database uses have a few key differences. Logical replication uses native PostgreSQL replication slots to record data-modifying statements or row changes on the replication source (primary) and reapply them on the replication target (replica). The primary and replica databases are separate and independent and can contain different datasets.</description></item><item><title>AWS ECS</title><link>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/AWS-ECS/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/AWS-ECS/</guid><description>What is ECS? ECS is Amazon their own take to make a container orchestrator, before surrendering to Kubernetes (therefore, [[AWS EKS]])
Components Task definition: define a job that will be run on the container(s), define also the container(s) resources. One task definition can create several tasks Task: is an instance of a task definition. Service: how many tasks you want to run for how long (at least this is my understanding) Resources What is the difference between a task and a service in AWS ECS?</description></item><item><title>Saving space in Terraform</title><link>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Saving-space-in-Terraform/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhenghe.hu/notes/Saving-space-in-Terraform/</guid><description>In [[Terraform]], by default terraform init will automatically download the providers/plugins and modules and place them under .terraform in the current working directory. This is very convenient as it treat each &amp;ldquo;Terraform project&amp;rdquo; as independent configuration.
At work as a [[DevOps]] engineer I have many AWS resources managed using Terraform and it is awesome. Each part is configured as separate &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo; this is very useful when it comes to debugging, also we find it more convenient not having to risk to affect the whole infrastructure while making changes on some part of it.</description></item></channel></rss>